<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Controller Optimizer</name>
    <directory>controlleroptimizer</directory>
    <id>3731198516</id>
    <description>[h2]Controller Optimizer[/h2]

This is a controller-focused input-feel mod, mainly intended to improve the unstable right-stick experience when using Brimstone in Repentance+.

[h2]Main Features[/h2]

[b]Brimstone input stabilization[/b]

When using the right stick to control Brimstone, stick recentering, snapback, or slight drift may cause the beam to stop early, fire in the wrong direction, or fail to fire fully.

This mod tries to make Brimstone fire fully in the correct direction and reduce abnormal interruptions caused by right-stick input.

[b]Schoolbag active item quick swap[/b]

This optional feature is enabled by default. While actually holding Schoolbag, you can use a controller button to quickly swap between two occupied active item slots. It can be disabled in Mod Config Menu.

The default button is right-stick press. This feature works with D Infinity, but it also works with other two-active-item setups.

[b]Mars accidental trigger guard[/b]

When holding Mars, left-stick movement may accidentally trigger a dash because of the analog input range.

This mod tries to prevent left-stick movement from triggering Mars, reducing accidental dashes for controller players.

[h2]Current Version[/h2]

[h2]Version 1.7.0 - Input-only compatibility hardening[/h2]

[b]Compatibility boundary[/b]

[list]
[*]Removed all code that inspected or changed player laser entities, lifetime, or shrink state.
[*]The mod now affects attacks only by returning filtered input values while the game is reading them.
[*]It never spawns Hemoptysis, Brimstone lasers, tears, damage, or charge completion.
[*]Player input state is isolated per character so shared-controller characters cannot reset or retrigger each other.
[*]Character state uses a stable engine identity so repeated Lua userdata wrappers cannot discard direction, release, or snapback history.
[/list]

[b]Azazel release behavior[/b]

[list]
[*]Removed the old 45-frame virtual direction hold that could keep Brimstone charging after the player returned the stick to center.
[*]Ordinary Azazel now leaves the game's triggered and pressed/released states native. The mod only stabilizes direction values and covers a two-frame input dropout.
[*]Full-charge attacks release promptly while retaining protection against brief controller sampling loss.
[/list]

[b]Tainted Azazel attack sequence[/b]

[list]
[*]A new stick attack creates exactly one native shoot trigger for Hemoptysis.
[*]Holding the stick continues the native charge without spawning attacks from Lua.
[*]The held direction is updated every frame, so the follow-up Brimstone can turn normally while charging.
[*]Returning the stick to center releases promptly and rearms the next cough only after a stable center input.
[/list]

[b]Snapback and direction accuracy[/b]

[list]
[*]Smooth turns remain immediate.
[*]A sudden near-180-degree input spike must remain stable briefly before it is accepted as an intentional turn.
[*]This prevents no-center stick snapback from reversing the final beam while still allowing a deliberate held 180-degree turn.
[/list]

[b]Analog Stick compatibility[/b]

When the Analog Stick item is held, the mod preserves the complete normalized 360-degree vector during the entire charge. The initial aim is no longer locked, and turning does not generate another Hemoptysis trigger.

[b]Compatibility principles[/b]

The mod only filters input values. It does not directly create Hemoptysis, Brimstone lasers, damage, or charge completion, and it does not modify laser lifetime or attack entities. Those remain controlled by the game.

Ordinary Brimstone keeps native pressed and triggered states. Familiar release compatibility is input-only and limited to the original Lil Brimstone and Lil Monstro. Unrelated and custom familiars are left untouched. Mars keeps native held movement state, and Schoolbag quick swap requires the real collectible, two occupied slots, and an unambiguous controller target.

Version 1.7.0 includes automated controller-input, conflict-boundary, shared-controller, Mars, Schoolbag, familiar-scope, and optional-API regression tests. Ordinary and Tainted Azazel, Analog Stick, Eye of the Occult, Lil Brimstone, Lil Monstro, Twisted Pair, Schoolbag, and D Infinity behavior were verified on Steam Deck before release.

[h2]Notes[/h2]

Mod Config Menu is optional. The mod works normally with its default settings even without MCM.

During normal gameplay, this mod does not display debug text on screen.

[h2]Maintenance[/h2]

I will continue maintaining this mod, but updates will be less frequent than before.

The original purpose of this mod is simply to improve the controller experience before the related Repentance+ issues are officially fixed.

Hopefully, controller players will eventually be able to fire Brimstone smoothly with the analog stick even without this mod.</description>
    <version>1.7.0</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
