<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Controller Optimizer</name>
    <directory>controlleroptimizer</directory>
    <id>3731198516</id>
    <description>[h2]Controller Optimizer[/h2]

This is a controller-focused input-feel mod, mainly intended to improve the unstable right-stick experience when using Brimstone in Repentance+.

[h2]Main Features[/h2]

[b]Brimstone direction hold[/b]

When using the right stick to control Brimstone, stick recentering, snapback, or slight drift may cause the beam to stop early, fire in the wrong direction, or fail to fire fully.

This mod tries to make Brimstone fire fully in the correct direction and reduce abnormal interruptions caused by right-stick input.

[b]Schoolbag active item quick swap[/b]

When holding Schoolbag, you can use a controller button to quickly swap between the two active item slots.

The default button is left-stick press. This feature works with D Infinity, but it also works with other two-active-item setups.

[b]Mars accidental trigger guard[/b]

When holding Mars, left-stick movement may accidentally trigger a dash because of the analog input range.

This mod tries to prevent left-stick movement from triggering Mars, reducing accidental dashes for controller players.

[h2]Current Version[/h2]

1.5.1 republishes the stable 1.3.2 behavior under a newer version number so
Steam and the game can replace installations that previously received 1.5.0.
There are no gameplay changes from 1.3.2.

[h2]Notes[/h2]

Mod Config Menu is optional. The mod works normally with its default settings even without MCM.

During normal gameplay, this mod does not display debug text on screen.

[h2]Maintenance[/h2]

I will continue maintaining this mod, but updates will be less frequent than before.

The original purpose of this mod is simply to improve the controller experience before the related Repentance+ issues are officially fixed.

Hopefully, controller players will eventually be able to fire Brimstone smoothly with the analog stick even without this mod.</description>
    <version>1.5.1</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
